## KEVIN JAMES DAVIES

info@kjd.me + 44 (0) 7515 880 728 http://kjd.me

## OBJECTIVES

To help build and contribute to a motivated team focused on communication through future-friendly design and web standards.

To use my design experience, technical knowledge, and creativity to achieve business excellence and build meaningful interactive experiences.

## SKILLS SUMMARY

I'm comfortable managing design & development teams, and have experience bridging the gaps which can develop between designers and developers. I'm also happy speaking with, and running workshops for, clients and colleagues.

I advocate a standards-based, future-friendly, mobile-first approach to web design and development.

Working in multi-cultural and multi-lingual environments in Canada, England, and Qatar have helped make me adaptable and have given me an acute awareness of the challenges and responsibilities we have as designers.

Code I am fluent in HTML5, CSS 3, and JavaScript/jQuery — I've been working with HTML 4 since the late 1990s. I have experience with both centralised (SVN and TFS) and decentralised (Git and Mercurial) source control management systems.

Design I have a solid understanding of design theory, and experience using grid systems and responsive design patterns for the web. I also have a very keen (read: slightly obsessive) interest in typography.

UX Cross channel UX design and content strategy are integral parts of my design process and I'm happy building and working through wireframes and clickable HTML/CSS prototypes with colleagues and clients.

Software I have more than two decades of experience with Adobe's desktop publishing software — specifically Photoshop, Illustrator, and more recently InDesign — currently part of the Adobe Creative Cloud.

Most of my day is spent in Web Inspector and BBEdit — I've been a BBEdit user since some time in 1998 — but I consider myself to be quite adaptable; I'm comfortable building and working in both physical and virtual Mac, Unix/Linux (and Windows) hosting and desktop environments.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Quintiles Inc UX & Front End Lead Medical Communications Since 2013 As the UX & Front End Lead for Quintiles — the world's leading provider of biopharmaceutical services — I manage the front end implementation and strategy for web-based applications and tools. Quintiles has helped develop or commercialise all of the top 50 best selling drugs on the market.

- Re-engineered the HTML/CSS front end of the in-house V3 portal framework.
- More than halved both the production and load times of the two key client-facing web applications by leveraging a front end framework, image optimisation, CSS preprocessing, web fonts, SVG, bundling & minification and conditional loading.
- Held a 40-person 'Lunch and Learn' workshop for the design, editorial, and account management teams on responsive web design, progressive enhancement and the benefits of adopting a future-friendly approach.

Kevin James Davies LTD Founder, Designer, Developer 2010 – 2013 After more than 10 years as an in-house designer, developer, and user experience specialist I opened a small creative studio in Oxford that built, among other things, responsive standards-based websites.

MEEZA Founding Designer 2009 – 2010 I relocated from the UK to Qatar to help build MEEZA's website and webbased tools from the ground up. MEEZA is a joint venture with the Qatar Foundation and has become Qatar's leading IT solutions & services provider.

Star Technology Services Engineering & UI Specialist 2005 – 2009

After working remotely for several months, Star recruited me from Canada to the UK to design and build the front end of Star's original managed services customer portal: StarPort.

Random Media Labs Co-Founder, Designer 2003 – 2005 Random Media Labs created HTML and Flash-based websites, content management systems, corporate identities, and hosting solutions for small & medium sized businesses in Toronto, Canada.

The Barnes Organisation
Web Designer
2001 – 2003

As the web designer for Canada's premier investor relations consulting firm, I worked directly with the Vice President of New Media to create hundreds of investor websites & presentations — raising billions in new capital for clients.

Bird On a Wire Networks Web Designer 2000 – 2001 Working directly under the Vice President of Sales & Marketing, I designed the corporate website, intranet, customer portal, and marketing collateral for Bird On A Wire, Canada's first high-end managed hosting provider.

Interlog Internet Services Software Developer 1997 – 1999 During the original dot-com era I built software kits and websites for one of Canada's first internet service providers. The kits and web-based guides enabled thousands of people to connect to the internet for the first time.

EDUCATION

University of British Columbia Vancouver, Canada Logic (Philosophy) and Astronomy Faculty of Arts